TAMMY FINA

5949 Blaverly Drive | New Albany, OH | 614-638-3086

Programmer / Network Admin / Instructor 10+ years experience

Who am I?

I am an IT professional that is currently building and fine-tuning my skills for full-stack web development or Dev/Ops. I successfully completed the Ohio State University College of Engineering Coding Boot Camp in April 2022. My previous IT work experience includes network administration, developing and teaching a computer science curriculum for a secondary school, and mainframe programming.

Work Experience

2000-2018

Took time away from professional career to raise four children and manage household. During that time, I worked in the following areas:

Feb 2018 - Present

IT Consultant

Trouble shooting software and hardware issues, web-site updates and search engine optimization

Sept 2015- Jan 2018

Pharmacy Technician

Assisted the pharmacist in duties related to running a pharmacy, including filling prescriptions, insurance claims, inventory, customer service and register

Feb 2012- Apr 2013

Financial Services Advisor | JP Morgan Chase

Maintained a successful record of problem resolution with Chase Card Services on the Freedom Knowledge team

Oct 2007 - Feb 2012

Benefits Coordinator | Colonial Life & Accident

Coordinated with benefits plan administrators to set up data requirements for initial and annual open enrollments. Assisted employees and plan administrators throughout the claims process

June 1991 - Dec 2000

Network Administrator | Secondary Computer Science and Math Teacher

Private K-12 School, Edmond, Oklahoma

- Built and managed a campus wide computer network including peer to peer,
 Ethernet, and fiber optic methodologies
- Instructor for Computer Science, Pascal Programming and Staff Training Classes
- Performed annual hardware and software upgrades for the school network including annual budget planning
- Created custom software solutions based on user specifications using MS Access

1989-1991

Oklahoma Corporation Commission

- Programmer/Analyst for state oil and gas and public utilities agency
- Developed vertical applications with COBOL and JCL in a mainframe environment
- DBMS programming on a mid-frame platform
- Constructed scripts to render screen forms and generate reports

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery
CLI, JSON, React, Node
Restful API, Express.js
MongoDB, SQL, MySQL
Agile Methodologies, GitHub
OOP, TDD, Jest
Database design and planning using Microsoft Access
Operating Systems using Windows Server NT

Education

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp, Ohio State University College of Engineering, April 2022

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics with a Minor in Computer Science • University of Oklahoma

Certifications

CIW Foundations - 2008 Life & Health 2006-2012 Series 6 and Series 63 Licenses 2006-2009 Mortgage Loan License 2006-2008